JOYCE WALTON R.N. Case Manager

VITALS 16701 Algonquin St. # F-112 Huntington Beach CA 92649 T 818 200-6416 E jjwaltrn@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

License Registered nurse with over 25 years Experience in utilization review, workers compensation And home health. Seeking a position as a telephonic/or Field Case Manager Position.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly skilled professional with strong communication skills
That provides quality care. Management service in a appropriate
Cost effective manner providing analysis regarding treatment
plans, outcome and problem areas. Able to work with clients, physician's employers
as well as other health care providers. Hands on experience with commercial,
Medicaid and Medicare lines of business.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient with Microsoft suite (word, Excel, Power Point, EZ cap, EZ care and Outlook). Extensive knowledge of Milliman, Interquel, Hippa Guidelines, CPT ICD Code, ODG, Medical terminology and care management, excellent communication skills.

EXPERIENCE

CASE MANAGEMENT SERVICES: 2013 CURRENT

*Field Case Manager

. Independent contractor providing Workers Compensation case Management and utilization review for multiple clients. Complete Coordination for patients with complex injuries that include Pain Management, Neurology, Orthopedic and Rehabilitation consults/ treatments.

- . Scheduling and attending appointments with patients to physicians offices to obtain progress and treatment recommendations as prescribed by the physicians as well as obtaining prior authorization of said recommendations, ordering equipment prescribed by physicians with approval from insurance adjusters.
- . Expedition of RTW by establishing a professional working relationship with client, physician, insurance company and employer.

BROADSPIRE, A CRAWFORD COMPANY, ATLANTA, GEORGIA

2008-2013 Case Manager/Field and Telephonic

- . Review of case records and reports while collecting and analyzing data to evaluate . a clients medical needs.
- . Meet with physician at appointments as well as telephonic to discuss treatment recommendations for the client to expedite the plans. To determine time spent in hospitals and make recommendations for rehab goals and return to work as well as discharge from hospital.
- . Conduct file reviews with insurance adjuster, Medical Director to advise them of case activity and directions.
- . Extensive travel to patients homes, health care providers, job sites and various offices
- . Educate the patients on his care, who to contact if emergency arise, evaluate home setting, so that patient is able to return to a safe environment with no physical home hazards.
- . Evaluate patients ADL's (Activity of daily living).
- . Successfully met monthly production and quality, cost savings assessment requirements.
- . Supervisor: Janet Bowman R.N.

DEPARTMENT OF LABO, SAN FRANCISCO CA

2003-2008 Workers compensation Case Manager, contract position for both field and onsite for the state of California/Field and onsite.

- . Medical management of patients with injuries employed by the United States Postal Service and Internal Revenue Service.
- . Attend appointments with patients to discuss treatment recommendations with physicians and see that patient follow thru. Discuss outcome of visits with insurance adjusters, employers, recommend a RTW with restrictions and job modification with employer when available.

- . Phone contact weekly with patients to discuss progress and compliance with. treatment recommendations prescribed by physician, contact other providers such as physical therapist to discuss progress.
- . Supervisor: Linda Rodriguez R.N.

VISITING NURSE ASSOCIATION/LOS ANGELES CA.

- . 1998-2003 Intake Coordinator/Field visiting.
- . Review file for medical intake. Determine insurance Private,. Medicaid, determine need for home health, discussed with nurses referring from hospitals, rehab, skilled nursing facilities.
- . Educate patients on their care with demonstrations for the diabetic patient, instructing on medications, wound care, signs to look for infection.
- . Wound care for severe decubitus and burns, with medication. Signs to look for regarding his wounds.
- . Well baby check, home visit to new mothers to instruct on care of infant.
- . Medication check.
- . Administer IV therapy.
- . Order medications for patients.
- . Contact physician if issues arise regarding care.
- . Charting.

OTHER RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

- . Concentra: Case manager
- . Aetna Health Insurance Utilization review, case management

Los Angeles County USC Medical Center Supervisor for surgical outpatient clinic.

EDUCATION
LOS ANGELES SOUTHWEST COLLEGE, WEST ATHENS, CA
ASSOCIATE DEGREE-NURSING

REFERENCES UPON REQUEST.